# Jeffrey Jessie

## **Military Police Officer - United States Army**

Clarksville, TN 37042 jejess6125@gmail.com 931-266-8462

United States Army Veteran, self-taught web developer and Army Reservist. Currently sitting at 15 years in the military and learning web development in my spare time to work towards a career change. Highly motivated and dedicated to creating amazing products.

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

## Work Experience

#### Wire Technician

AT&T - Nashville, TN June 2015 to Present

Install internet, home phone and cable television using CATV cable, coaxical cable Install satellite television utilizing DirecTV equipment Install Fiber internet

## Military Police Officer

United States Army - Fort Campbell, KY July 2004 to Present

Implemented new case input procedures effectively increasing case production efficiency to 85%

- Conduct high quality training for groups up to 60 employees
- Submit comprehensive and timely reports to supervisor
- Work under pressure, multi-tasked, and met tight deadlines
- Plan, coordinate, direct and update law enforcement procedures for assigned jurisdiction of 300 personnel
- Instituted working relationship with local law enforcement resulting in cross training opportunities
- Planned and directed UFC event security and site operations involving over 1000 personnel without injury

## Education

#### **AA** in General Studies

Hopkinsville Community College - Fort Campbell, KY

#### Skills

HTML 5 (1 year), CSS3 (1 year), Javascript (Less than 1 year), Python (Less than 1 year), Express JS (Less than 1 year), Next.js (Less than 1 year), MongoDB (Less than 1 year)

#### Links

## https://j3ffjessie.github.io

# Military Service

**Branch: United States Army** Service Country: United States

Rank: SSG

July 2004 to Present

Military Police Non-Commissioned Officer. Highly skilled and trained in multiple areas of expertise. Special Reaction Team certified entry team leader, Special Reaction Team certified Marksman Observer. Traffic Management and Collision Investigations certified ASI Q9. Instructor/Facilitator certified.

# Certifications/Licenses

## **Responsive Web Design Certification**

July 2018 to Present

Responsive Web Design Certification from FreeCodeCamp.org representing 300 Hours of Coursework.

https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/nahera/responsive-web-design

## Assessments

## **Critical Thinking — Highly Proficient**

March 2019

Measures a candidate's ability to use logical approaches when solving problems. Full results: https://share.indeedassessments.com/share\_assignment/7hnh48bqosjdttx0

Indeed Assessments provides skills tests that are not indicative of a license or certification, or continued development in any professional field.

#### Additional Information

#### Areas of Expertise:

- Strategic Planning
- Quality Control
- Process Improvement
- Customer Service
- Program Management
- Team Building
- Client Relationships
- Facilities / Safety Management